Zakaria Abdessamed Brahimi Django/React Developer & Product Manager

brahimi.zakaria.abdessamed@gmail.com | +213 665915411



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-oriented and problem solver with 2 years of experience building and maintaining software/website. Highly skilled in communication, collaboration, finding solutions, and determining customer satisfaction. I'm a huge fan of team management, I love to manage teams and work together to build real-world products.

I'm looking for opportunities on Django/React Developer & Product Manager (internships, remote offers,...etc.) with an ambitious and growing team that is tackling a major problem.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- ✓ Programming languages: Python, Javascript
- ✓ Web Frameworks: Django, React
- ✓ Front-end & back-end web development
- ✓ HTML, CSS, Tailwindcss

- Database Management: PostgreSQL
- Agile software development
- ✓ Data Structure and Algorithms
- ✓ Source control: Git/GitHub

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Moustachir

Freelance Web Developer | 20 December, 2022 - Present

- Write well-designed and efficient code by using the best software development practices.
- Collaborate with company developers to update the website and create new features.
- Built and maintained websites for Moustachir's clients through various online platforms.

The Sparks Foundation

Remote Internship | January, 2022 - March, 2022

- Created and tested applications for several websites.
- Created guides to document the processes of completing the given tasks.

Alpha Center, Batna

Web development Instructor | May, 2021 - March, 2022 | Video Source

- Taught how the internet works and Practiced HTML, CSS, Git, Tailwindcss, and Javascript.
- Covered advanced frontend skills such as flexbox/ grid/ Asynchronous JavaScript/ and a little bit of react js framework.
- built together several web apps such as todo app, URL shortener, landing page, and others.

Data Structure & Algo on Leetcode

Problem Solving Skills | Leetcode Profile

• Solved 124 Problems on leetcode in different Data structures and algorithms

EDUCATION

University of Batna 2 (Mostefa Ben Boulaïd) | 2018 - 2021

Bachelor of Computer Science - Software Engineering

Higher National School of Management | 2021 - May 2023

Master of Entrepreneurship and Project Management

RELEVANT PROJECTS

Hashnode Clone

- Blogging platform and community of developers that enables you to publish articles developed by Django Rest Framework and Reactjs
- Code Source | Live Review | Original Platform

Medium Clone

- Medium-like web Application using React js and Django Rest Framework
- Code Source | Original Platform

Front end Mentor

- A platform where you can solve real-world HTML, CSS, and JavaScript challenges
- Profile Link

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE

Google Developers Students Club

Community Leader and Founder | Jul 2020 - Aug 2021

- Oversee and maintain core web services and websites
- Write well-designed and efficient code by using the best software development practices
- Collaborate with senior developers to update the website and create new features

TEDx Batna 2 University

Team Lead | Apr 2021 - Jun 2022

- Built and maintained websites for clients through various online platforms
- Created and tested applications for websites
- Created guides to document the processes and maintain business continuity

Teachstars Startup Weekend - Tipaza

Lead Organizer | 03 February, 2022 - Present

• a three-day program where aspiring entrepreneurs can experience startup life. In hundreds of cities around the world.

Student Communities and Clubs

Speaking Sessions & Workshops

- Designed, taught, and evaluated 12 workshops and sessions Presented to groups of over 160 people in student information sessions.
- Taught and mentored in Python, Web development, Agile, and Leadership skills to more than 167 students during Python/Web Bootcamps, and soft skills Courses.

CFM - Club des Future Managers

Club President at Higher national School of Management | May, 2022 - Present

• The club's mission is to encourage students to enter the entrepreneurship & project management world and grow their knowledge in a peer-to-peer learning environment.

ZakariaBrahimi